HARSHAV KUMAR

harshavk97@gmail.com • GitHub • LinkedIn • (+91) 8295242101 • Gurgaon, India

SUMMARY

Creative and people-oriented machine learning engineer with up to 3 years of working in a tech startup. Highly experienced in writing codes and algorithms as well as building complex neural networks, have the ability to define a personal research roadmap. Possess an unbridled passion for artificial intelligence with comprehensive knowledge of deep learning, machine learning concepts and other related technologies. Led and managed a team of 5 in developing new software from concept to delivery.

EXPERIENCE

RMgX Technologies LLP, Gurugram, Haryana | September 2019 – Present

Machine Learning Engineer

- Implemented object masking for object removal from images achieving 0.82 IOU.
- Generated 50k synthetic data points for automatic license plate recognition base model achieving 0.6 CER.
- Reduced average waiting time of students from 5 mins to 30 seconds on online proctoring-based exams by integrating face recognition and camera tampering detection and speech detection in existing platform.
- Improved upon handwriting recognition model by utilizing Dilated CNN and multi-directional LSTM decoder achieving 0.72 CER.
- Improved performance of SOTA models on crowd density estimation by 60% by developing a multi-patch ensemble.

MTX IT Consulting Services Private Limited, Jaipur, Rajasthan | January 2019 - March 2019

Artificial Intelligence Intern

- Achieved 82% person re-identification after obstruction in video feeds by building up on state of the art algorithm.
- Integrated and deployed low latency (20FPS) ML models on edge camera modules.
- Lead the skill development process for in-house AI virtual assistant.

CSIR-CEERI, Pilani, Rajasthan | May 2018 - January 2019

Summer Student Research Trainee

- Implemented digital signal processing-based modules for structural health monitoring application.
- Developed an air quality monitoring system.
- Utilized ARIMA model to predict 7 days air quality with 5% MAE.
- Analyzed patterns in building structure health over a period of 1 month using the response frequencies

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: Python, C/C++, MySQL

Frameworks and Tools: TensorFlow, Keras, OpenCV, Git, Flask (REST Framework) **Key Skills**: Machine Learning, Computer Vision, NLP, TensorFlow, PvTorch

PAPER AND PUBLICATIONS

- <u>Controversy Probability Prediction on Twitter Corpus</u> (ITEE Journal) | October 2020
- <u>Door Security using Face Detection and Raspberry PI</u> (IOP Publication) | March 2018

PERSONAL PROJECTS

ResCode | January 2021

- Implemented and reproduced 5 research papers (ongoing project) from top conferences
- Provided OPEN-SOURCE implementations in top Machine learning frameworks
- Created an EASY-TO-USE API with a plug and play architecture

ADDNET | SEPTEMBER - OCTOBER 2020

- Advertisement placement onto live video feed without distorting pixels and placing at suitable position with respect to the person in feed.
- It's based on DeepLabV3 architecture.

WORD OR LINE SEGMENTATION | DECEMBER 2019

- Implemented algorithm to generate and extract text segments from handwritten texts.
- Provided a low latency open-source implementation with 0.2ms result extraction.
- Obtained a mAP of 75 on word level segmentation of student notes.

ACHIEVEMENTS

- Winners: RMgX Productathon | December 2019 & December 2021
- Innovator Title: RMgX Technologies annual star performer | May 2021
- Regional Finalist in DRUSE-DRDO Govt. Competition | February 2018

EDUCATION

BK Birla Institute of Engineering & Technology, Pilani, Rajasthan | August 2015 - May 2019 Bachelor of Science in Computer Science & Engineering | 72% (Hons.)